<news>
<recent_items>
    <item>
        <when>Spring 2026</when>
        <what>This summer, I will be attending <a href="https://cs2026.sciencesconf.org/">Curves and Surfaces 2026</a> in Saint-Malo; <a href="https://math-events.uni-bonn.de/event/598/">New Mathematical Methods in Geometry Processing</a> in Bonn; <a href="https://sgp26.org/">SGP 2026</a> in Bern and <a href="https://s2026.siggraph.org/">Siggraph 2026</a> in Los Angeles. If you're planning on attending any of them and want to meet up, <a href="mailto:$GMAIL">let me know!</a></what>
    </item>
    <item>
        <when>Dec. 2025</when>
        <what>This year I will be serving on the committees for SIGGRAPH 2026 &amp; SGP 2026, and serving as graduate school chair for SGP 2026.</what>
    </item>
    <item>
        <when>Jul. 2025</when>
        <what>This summer, I will be attending <a href="https://sgp2025.my.canva.site/">SGP 2025</a> in Bilbao and <a href="https://s2025.siggraph.org/">Siggraph</a> in Vancouver.</what>
    </item>
    <item>
        <when>Apr. 2024</when>
        <what>I accepted an assistant professor position at the <a href="https://www.cs.utah.edu/">University of Utah's Kahlert School of Computing</a>! I will start in fall 2026.</what>
    </item>
</recent_items>
<extra_items>
    <item>
    <when>Dec. 2024</when>
        <what>I will serve on the program committee for the 2025 <a href="https://sgp2025.my.canva.site/">Symposium on Geometry Processing (SGP)</a>.</what>
    </item>
    <item>
        <when>Sept. 2024</when>
        <what>I started a postdoc with Mathieu Desbrun at École Polytechnique.</what>
    </item>
    <item>
        <when>Aug. 2024</when>
        <what><a href="Research/harnack-tracing/index.html">Ray Tracing Harmonic Functions</a> and <a href="Research/solid-knitting/index.html">Solid Knitting</a> were both awarded <a href="https://blog.siggraph.org/2024/06/siggraph-2024-technical-papers-awards-best-papers-honorable-mentions-and-test-of-time.html/">Best Paper Honorable Mentions</a> at Siggraph 2024.</what>
    </item>
    <item>
        <when>May 2024</when>
        <what>I defended my <a href="Research/Thesis/thesis.pdf">PhD thesis</a> at CMU.</what>
    </item>
    <item>
        <when>Aug. 2023</when>
        <what>I was invited to attend the <a href="https://www.geometrie.tugraz.at/events/og2023.html">geometry workshop in Obergurgl</a>, which was relocated to Innsbruck due to flooding in Ötztal valley.</what>
    </item>
    <item>
        <when>Apr. 2019</when>
        <what>The National Science Foundation awarded me a Graduate Research Fellowship.</what>
    </item>
</extra_items>
</news>